Arghya Bandyopadhyay

C-608 Green view colony • Raigarh, Chhattisgarh • 496001 Mobile No. 7224077631 • EMAIL arghyab13bga@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Been a Software engineer at NatWest Group for 3 Months and a Full Stack Developer with 2 years' of professional experience in terms of freelancing and an extensive range of skills including Java and Flutter. I have been writing codes using Java since when I was in class 9 and have a very thorough hold on the language. I also work on open source projects and believe that all the codes written by me shouldn't be rewritten.

PROFILE

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/arghya-bandyopadhyay-836a93141.

Github: http://github.com/arghyabandyopadhyay .

EDUCATION

2020-2022 | Master of Technology

National Institute of Technology Durgapur, Mahatma Gandhi Rd, A-Zone, Durgapur, West Bengal 713209

I have secured an aggregate of CPI: 9.29

2016-2020 | Bachelor of Technology

Shri Shankaracharya Group of Institutions, Junwani, Bhilai (C.G.), India 490020 I have secured an aggregate of 79.49% and CPI: 8.72

2014-2016 | Class 10+2

O.P. Jindal School, Raigarh (C.G.), India 496001 91.6% Final Marks

SKILLS

Java, Flutter, Database, Game Theory, Node.js, Express.js, Linux, Full Stack Development.

EXPERIENCE

Jul 2022 - Current | NatWest Group

Software Engineer

Responsibilities: Design and develop reusable libraries and application programming interfaces for use across the bank. Design and develop software that is amenable for a greater automation of build, release testing and deployment process on all environments. Support the reuse and sharing of platform components and technologies within the software engineering teams. Deliver software components to enable the delivery of platforms, applications and services. Write unit and integration tests, in automated test environments to ensure code quality.

May 2020 - Jul 2022 | Self-Employed

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities: Pixel-perfect implementation of our approved user interface. Design and deployment of our database and REST API. Integrating our front-end UI with the constructed API. Development of Mobile Applications for Android and IOS. And Integration of applications with Firebase.

Sep 2020 – May 2022 | National Institute Of Technology

Teaching Assistant

Responsibilities: Carrying out research work on game theoretic model formulation of kidney exchange program for Indian medical space. Assisting the conduction of lab classes on Advanced Data Structure and Algorithms.

Feb 2020 - Mar 2020 | Anvy Technologies

Full Stack Developer (Internship)

Responsibilities: Make the projects using Java(JavaFx), Laravel(Php, Ajax, Javascript, Jquery). Conduct software analysis, programming, testing and debugging. Ensuring the quality of code and deliverable is high.

Jul 2018 – Sep 2018 | Vedas Technocrats

Java Developer (Internship)

Responsibilities: Make the projects using JavaFX. Conduct software analysis, programming, testing and debugging. Ensuring the quality of code and deliverable is high.

RESEARCH

March 2021 – May 2022 | Kidney Exchange problem(Game Theory)

I worked on how to adapt to the kidney exchange problem in India. What are the problems faced in kidney exchange and what can be solutions. This problem is categorised under mechanism design.

PROJECTS

June 2021 - Current | Open source ERP(Javafx, Css)

I started this project as an initiative to create an ERP which is open source. There are very few free, open source ERPs running in the market.

Jan 2021 – Current | Fee management and Video lecture streaming application(Flutter)

The project is basically intended for Gym owners/trainers and also for zumba classes. The application enables the users to keep a track of the payment dates, dues and other payment related stuff. And also paid video lectures.

May 2020 – Nov 2021 | An Mobile Application Module for an ERP (Flutter)

The application is intended for the owners out of station or town, but need to get updates of their business. The app is much more than the update with features like order punchings, invoice generation and many others.

Mar 2020 - Nov 2020 | Online Customer Order Punching Application (Flutter)

Started with a vision of an application which is used in restaurants, by the waiters to punch orders and eventually also allow the customers to punch the orders by themselves. Now it is being adapted for other verticals too.

Feb 2020 – Mar 2020 | Inventory Management Application (Laravel)

This was a website developed for a gold warehouse in order to manage its inventory and to assign inventory goods to the workers. There were basically two intended users for the website, the admin and the agents.

Feb 2020 – Mar 2020 | Billing Software for a Tailoring Shop (JavaFx)

A normal billing and pseudo accounting software for a tailor shop. The entire project was made using JavaFX.

Sep 2019 – Apr 2020 | Student Attendance System Using Face Recognition (Python)

A student's attendance system working on a face recognition system using opency. There was a feature of assignments being shown based on the face recognition. It also has a bulk message sending feature.

Oct 2015 – Dec 2015 | Digital India Software (Java Swing)

The Software was intended to issue documents for people, it was just an idea converted into an application. The Languages used were Java and Sql.

Oct 2015 – Dec 2015 | Java Quiz (Java Swing)

KBC type Quiz Developed in Java.